<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ScrollingText</string>
    <string name="article_title">Babylon (2022 film)</string>
    <string name="article_subtitle">Babylon Wikipedia Page</string>
    <string name="article_text"><b><i>Babylon</i></b> is a 2022 American epic period black comedy-drama film written and directed by Damien Chazelle. It features an ensemble cast including Brad Pitt, Margot Robbie, Diego Calva, Jean Smart, Jovan Adepo and Li Jun Li. It chronicles the rise and fall of multiple characters during Hollywood\'s transition from silent to sound films in the late 1920s.
\n\n<b>Plot:</b>\n
In 1926 Los Angeles, Mexican immigrant Manuel "Manny" Torres helps transport an elephant to a debauched, drug-fueled bacchanal at a Kinoscope Studios executive\'s mansion. He quickly becomes smitten with Nellie LaRoy, a brash, ambitious self-declared "star" from New Jersey. As they snort cocaine, Manny reveals his wish to be part of something bigger. While the elephant walks through, distracting partygoers, Manny helps carry away young actress Jane Thornton, who overdosed on drugs during a urolagniac act with sizable actor Orville Pickwick.

\n\n
Also attending are Chinese-American lesbian cabaret singer Lady Fay Zhu and African-American jazz trumpeter Sidney Palmer. The flamboyantly-dancing Nellie is spotted and swiftly recruited to replace Jane in a Kinoscope film; during filming, she crudely upstages the star. Manny meets and befriends Jack Conrad, a benevolent but troubled, oft-married film star, and drives a drunken Jack home, who helps Manny secure assistant jobs at Kinoscope (like finding a new camera to film an outdoors scene with Jack before nightfall); Manny climbs the studio system\'s ranks.

\n\n
Nellie quickly becomes an "it girl" covered by gossip columnist Elinor St. John, who also follows Jack\'s career. As sound film displaces silents in the late-1920s, Manny skillfully adapts to technical changes, eventually attaining directorial jobs. Nellie struggles to navigate sound film\'s demands, and increases her drug use and reckless gambling, tarnishing her reputation despite Manny\'s assistance.

\n\n
Nellie, shown to have an institutionalized mother, eggs on her drunken father (and inept business-manager) Robert to publicly fight a rattlesnake during a party; he passes out. Nellie fights the snake, which bites her neck; Fay kills it and sucks out the venom. Nellie passionately kisses her.

\n\n
By 1932, Jack begins to sense that his popularity has waned, but still works in low-budget MGM films. Meanwhile, Sidney has secured his own musical film and orchestra.

\n\n
As Hollywood becomes less libertine, executives tell Manny to fire Fay, a Kinoscope title writer, because of her perceived lesbian affair with Nellie. While practicing lines with new wife Estelle, Jack is devastated to learn his longtime friend/producer, George Munn, has committed suicide.

\n\n
Elinor and Manny attempt to revamp Nellie\'s image and ingratiate her into Hollywood\'s high society, but at a party with William Randolph Hearst and Marion Davies, Nellie lashes out against upper-class snobbery, vomiting on Hearst.

\n\n
Jack finds Elinor\'s cover story about his declining popularity and confronts her; she explains that although his star has faded, he will be immortalized on film. Sidney is offended when studio executives convince Manny to request he use makeup to darken his skin for Southern audiences. Upon completion, Sidney leaves Kinoscope.

\n\n
Meanwhile, eccentric gangster James McKay threatens Nellie\'s life over her massive gambling debts. Manny initially rejects her pleas for help, but later secures funds from on-set drug-pusher/aspiring actor "The Count", and visits James with him to pay off Nellie\'s debt. Manny panics upon learning the money is fake, made by his own prop-maker. James invites the men to a subterranean gathering-space for animal-abusing debauched parties, raving about potential film ideas. When James realizes the cash is fake, he attempts to kill them, but they narrowly escape, killing James\' henchman Wilson.

\n\n
Jack encounters Fay at a hotel party; she reveals her departure for Europe and Pathé. Afterwards, a despondent Jack returns to his hotel room, fatally shooting himself in the head.

\n\n
Manny asks Nellie to flee with him to Mexico, marry, and start a new life. She resists, but eventually agrees. However, James\' associate tracks Manny down, killing The Count and his roommate but sparing Manny\'s life if Manny leaves Los Angeles. Meanwhile, Nellie reneges on her decision and dances away into the night.

\n\n
A montage reveals newspaper clippings detailing Nellie being found dead in a hotel room at 34, and Elinor\'s death at age 76.

\n\n
In 1952, Manny returns to California with his wife Silvia and young daughter, having fled to New York City and established a radio shop. He shows them the Kinoscope Studios entrance, but visits a nearby cinema alone to see Singin\' in the Rain; the film\'s depiction of the industry\'s transition from silents to talkies moves him to tears. A century-spanning series of vignettes from numerous films follows. As the focus returns to Singin\' in the Rain, Manny smiles.

    </string>
</resources>